Valentine Taylor

Westside, Robert Road, Hedgerley, South Bucks, SL2 3XS

Tel: +44 (0) 1753 648 903 / +44 (0) 7967 449 523 **Email:** taylorval_601@hotmail.com

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY PROFESSIONAL

I am an experienced IT Support professional with 2nd & 3rd line experience in Windows & Mac environments.

Effectively lead, manage and deliver positive results both individually and within a team. I have an excellent record in delivering within many roles.

With over 15 years experience supporting multi-national corporations and SME's, I have commercial awareness and understand end-user requirements, expectations and communicate effectively, empathically and clearly.

I adapt to office and field-based environments easily and have travelled extensively across the world to support, train and lead projects.

Best results come from good relationships. Being the go-to person is a position I take seriously. Listening is important and by instilling confidence with honesty, empathy and optimism you can achieve lasting success.

Education:

Kingston University

September 1995 - June 1998

BSc Degree in Aerospace Engineering with Mechanical

Uxbridge Technical Collage

September 1992 – June 1995

BTEC National Diploma in Mechanical Engineering

Employment:

Siteminder

December 2018 – present

Role: ICT Site Administrator

Siteminder hired me to audit, update and manage the IT systems in their London office as well as plan risk assessments and rollouts for Windows, Mac, printer and VoIP system migrations.

Additional duties include managing the network, Wi-Fi, hardware, PBX, purchasing, on-boarding and training.

Tasks include:

- Configuring & administering Mac OSX & Windows 7,8 & 10 laptops
- Google Admin administration (Mail, Apps, Groups, Drive)
- Google Bits for A/V & video conferencing/meetings
- Managing and configuring Office 365
- Install and configure Windows 2012 server
- Cisco Meraki network administration
- Samange Ticketing system
- Installing and configuring VMWare & Parallels
- Administering PBX, Tenfold, FOP telephony systems
- Configuration of physical & soft phones
- 8x8 IP phone administration
- Administering Salesforce, Workday & Slack

Day-to-day duties consisted of building and updating laptops with software, working with sales teams to update and troubleshoot phone issues, administer the network through the Cisco Meraki, administer Gmail for all users. Additionally I managed the purchasing of IT equipment.

I managed an office of 100+ users across various departments, from 50% sales teams (French, Spanish, Latin America, German & UK), developers, marketing, HR & facilities.

Joinery Space Limited

January 2018 – October 2018

Role: Part-Time - IT Rollout Manager

Joinery Space hired me to assist with a design cost and build project.

This involved working out pricing, sourcing equipment and building a bespoke environment that conformed to the clients needs.

As the IT budget was small my goal was to source equipment from a variety of suppliers that were fit for purpose, reliable & safe.

Tasks include:

- Configuring Mac & Windows laptops
- Installing and configuring Office 365
- Install and configure Windows 2012 server File/Print Services
- · Automating and optimising Macs for Windows features
- Installing and configuring Parallels
- Installing AutoCAD 2018
- Installing and supporting Google Sketch-up
- Updating and maintaining Joineryspace.com

In addition to this task, I assisted with joinery work to design and build a bespoke audio environment for the client that included various speaker configurations and a sound treated internal room.

WeWork

October 2015 – December 2017

Role: Senior Technology Lead/Corp Tech

Initially hired to lead & support a team of 1st & 2nd line staff across 7 offices in London & EMEA.

Primary duties consist of managing ticket count, reviewing & streamlining processes, creating standard practise documents/manuals and mentoring/working with community teams.

Technical duties consist of VOIP, networking, printing, A/V support as well as logistics, software/hardware rollouts and purchasing.

Prior to my arrival WeWork, IT teams in the US managed support remotely. The time difference as well as lack of physical support resulted in a number of inefficiencies and impracticalities leading to frustration and low output.

Within my first 4 weeks the IT ticket count reduced by 75% with members and employees able to work effectively bringing greater confidence in IT. I made significant inroads into the brief I was given.

Additionally, I was seconded to sites in Chicago, New York and Austin to assist staff with technical & procedural challenges.

WeWork is a BYOD environment. Challenges when integrating equipment into this environment occur regularly. With clear communication and innovation I've successfully managed relationships with members own equipment whilst adhering to WeWork standards.

I look for solutions and am confident in reaching compromises for members allowing them to operate within the environment.

I regularly met my team to review processes, challenges, outstanding tickets & tasks and company information. We debriefed in an open forum to discuss matters.

I believe in authenticity, honesty and openness. I'm always available for the team.

Tasks included:

- Reviewing, managing and implementing processes for 1st/2nd line and CM teams
- Building and administering Windows 2012 Server
- AD Administration (managing/creating user accounts/groups)
- Configuring and supporting iOS devices
- Configuring and deploying Kyocera & HP network printers
- Configuring and supporting CUPS Mac print server
- Configuring and supporting PaperCut printer management server
- Configuring HP/Kyocera printers on mixed Windows/Mac platforms
- Procuring, deploying and configuring Polycom and Konfitel VOIP phones
- Maintaining relationships with 3rd party vendors, for logistics and service management
- Mac & Windows builds and deployment
- Cisco Meraki network management
- Ruckus network management

- Supervise 3rd party hardware, configurations and installations
- Office move management, re-patching and testing
- A/V Crestron/Enplug/Air Media v/c systems configuring and maintenance
- Working with Ops & maintenance to ensure all new offices are fitted with correct equipment, fully tested and ready for use.
- Rollout scheduling for hardware/software deployment
- ZenDesk Call logging
- VMWare installs and configuration
- Office audits for wifi management
- Purchasing hardware/software & services
- New office openings scheduling, supervising and troubleshooting.
- Bettercloud administration/management
- Centrify management and rollouts

Additional responsibilities consisted of supporting London, Netherlands, Germany & Israel HQ staff for all build, hardware, access and software support.

Joinery Space Limited

October 2011 – June 2015

Role: Part-Time -IT Project Manager

Hired to design, cost, build and support a SME infrastructure supporting 6 office-based users.

Requirements included network design & installation, file & print services, data storage, security, CCTV security and wifi/internet access.

As the IT budget was small my goal was to source equipment from a variety of suppliers that were fit for purpose, reliable & safe.

Tasks include:

- Configuring Dell PC's with Windows 7/8
- Installing and configuring Office 2010
- Install and configure File/Print Services
- Automating and optimising PC's for Windows features
- Installing AutoCAD 2013
- Installing and supporting Google Sketch-up
- Installing and configuring Cisco wireless network
- Installing and configuring Y-Cam CCTV cameras

- Installing and configuring Brother mfp for sharing
- Installing and configuring HP plotter
- Google Apps & Drive for file storage
- Set up RAID 5 backup machine
- AutoCAD design & planning

I succeeded in achieving this goal and am still consulted for support and maintenance.

Broadgate Estates Limited

May 2014 - October 2014

Role: IT Support Supervisor

Hired to supervise a small service desk team performing 2nd &-3rd line support to a user base of 300+ based in locations around London. Technical support included troubleshooting, installations and rollouts of hardware/software in a mixed Windows/Mac based environment.

Technical Tasks Include:

- AD Administration (managing/creating user accounts/groups)
- Desktop & laptop support (Windows 7 64-bit)
- Desktop & laptop configuration (software updates/rebuilds)
- Sophos AV support and configuration
- Star Printer support and configuration
- Network printing (setting up queues, installation and support)
- Googlemail administration and support (email, calendar, contacts)
- Google Android Nexus phone (configuration and support)
- **iPad Air** (configuration and support)
- Blackberry (configuration and support)
- Maas 360 for mobile devices
- Office 365 for mobile devices
- Office 2010 support
- MITEL IP PBX phone system administration, configuration and support
- Cherwell call logging system
- Daily backup checks and job logging
- · Documentation and record maintenance on in-house Wiki
- Dameware & Remote Desktop

Administrative Tasks Include

- Objective advice on IT planning within the business
- Team well-being and opportunities
- Client/team relationships/improvements/opportunities
- Hardware/Software/Application Projects & rollouts
- · Purchasing and vendor management
- IT Service Desk management
- Budgets, scheduling and resourcing

Weekly site visits in and around London both individually and as part of a team included working with site teams to understand their needs, concerns and opportunities to improve IT service.

Additionally I assisted with installing and configuring hardware (PC's, printers, phones, cabling, routers, switches, etc), decommissioning equipment and troubleshooting hardware & software related issues.

Herbalife Europe Limited

August 2013 – December 2013

Role: IS Support Engineer III

Hired as 2^{nd} / 3^{rd} line support to service 60+ office-based users in a mixed Windows/Mac environment.

Tasks Include:

- Desktop support with1st and 2nd line user support skills
- Windows 2003/Windows 2008 server platform
- Maintenance and configuration of Raid 5 disk arrays configuration and maintenance
- Patching/Switches/Router support
- Backup Exec support
- Windows XP, Windows 7
- Microsoft Office 2003 2010 (Excel/Word/PowerPoint/Access)
- Microsoft Office 2011 for Mac
- Microsoft Outlook 2003 2010
- Mac OSX 10.7, 10.8, OSX Server
- Mobile device support including Blackberry, IOS devices
- Documentation and record maintenance
- Wireless router support and configuration

- Dell, Mac, Cisco and Xerox printer hardware support & configuration
- HP mobile printer configuration and installation
- Clickshare installation for Video conferencing
- Rackstation backups and storage
- Service Now (SNOW) Call logging
- VMware/Parallels/Virtual Box virtualisation installation and configuration

As well as day-to-day support I also prepared hardware/software/licencing inventories, hardware rollouts, software updates and successfully managed the XP to W7 migration of 150+ desktops and laptops within a 6-week window.

Created formal documentation for various processes including builds, backups, user guides and bespoke process.

Liaised with various hardware vendors for maintenance and support contracts. Worked with users based in the UK and EMEA regions on a daily basis.

BurgerKing Limited

February 2006 – December 2012

Role: MIS Support Manager/PoS Support Manager

After years of working within a successful support team, I was tasked with managing the IT service desk team in the UK & EMEA. Our team of 6 had a wonderful relationship with a mix of technical excellence, people management and experience within corporates.

My experience of relationship management as well as technical exposure and growth allowed me to influence, promote and raise the profile of the MIS team within a challenging environment.

My team managed a user base in Northern Europe (UK, Netherlands & Sweden)

Projects supported and managed included:

- MS Windows 2000/XP/Vista/Windows 7
- MS Windows Server 2003
- MS Office Suite 2000/2003/2007
- MS Map Point 2004/2006
- Oracle, SAP, SQL
- VOIP phones implementation
- AD configuration
- MS Share Point 2010
- Video Conferencing support (Lifesize)

- Remedy/Service Centre call management
- Dameware/LANDesk/Remote Desktop remote consoles
- VMWare installation
- Ghost software installation and migration
- SOX Complicacy
- Ethernet/Networking/IP support/configuration (software and hardware)
- HP Printer maintenance/installation/monitoring (local and network)
- Windows 2000/2003 server support & configuration
- PoS Micros terminal configuration (restaurant systems)

•

In 2008 I was seconded to company restaurant support (PoS). This was a dual capacity as I maintained my MIS Support duties. PoS Support included maintaining back-office restaurant PC's, printing and network hardware, O/S troubleshooting and maintenance, installations/upgrades and misc hardware support (cabling, routers, monitors).

Returned as full-time Helpdesk support leader in 2010

Key Projects/Achievements:

- Lead helpdesk and 3rd party team of technicians to successfully upgrade operating systems including Windows NT-2000 & 2000-XP and XP to Windows 7.
- Budgeted, planned and Lead teams to install & upgraded numerous software applications including MS Office, SAP, Oracle, SQ in UK and Sweden RSC and for field users.
- Worked extensively with PoS team to upgrade all company restaurant back-office PC's from Windows NT- XP as well as support in-house systems for reporting, polling and validating financial data.
- Successfully implemented of hardware/software/LAN/WAN configuration for new RSC in Holland. Managed the training program for new/transitioned users to settle in and work smoothly within their new environment.
- Worked with IT relocation team to successfully relocate the UK RSC twice. Uxbridge to Stockely park in 2007 and Stockley Park to Slough in 2009. Tasks included hardware/software configuration/testing (functionality for desktops, printers, Internet, Intranet LAN, WAN), vendor management, logistics and end-user management.
- Reduced business IT spending on several numerous occasions with resourceful planning and cost-effective analysis including data retrieval, negotiating contracts with suppliers/vendors and effective communication to users regarding data management.
- Oversaw UK migration of restaurant systems from UK office to franchisees in 2012 with global partner ensuring that UK office completed a smooth migration with zero downtime.
- Oversaw UK migration of UK SAN in 2012 to data centre in Germany assisting global partner with this project. Again, completed with zero downtime to the business.

Aside from the invaluable technical growth, project challenges and working within a volatile business my real buzz was using my personality to bridge gaps between end-users and IT.

Setting realistic, honest expectations to forge trusting relationships is what makes life meaningful. And to lay down foundations for this as a standard was a fabulous achievement.

BurgerKing Limited

February 2000 – January 2006

Role: MIS Support Analyst

Following my successful management of the Y2K project I was contracted to work within the UK RSC (UK HQ) with the laptop/desktop support team,

Tasks Include:

- Working with and supported a team of IT analysts for all software/hardware/environment support including analysis/troubleshooting/maintenance.
- Supported an EMEA user base of more than 600 people in 8 European countries
- Training IT helpdesk/third-parties for patches/fixes, implementations, company IT standards.
- Third-party & vendor account management
- Leading project-based teams for various projects including office moves and rollouts
- Ensuring SLA's were adhered to as effectively as possible.
- Documentation and record management
- Data backup management

BurgerKing Limited

February 1999 – January 2000

Role: Y2K Project Lead

Hired as member of Y2K project team to test, validate and organise scheduling for hardware and software compliance within sites across UK.

This included visits to HQ in Madrid, Gothenburg and Munich as we as back-end testing in over 100 restaurants across the UK

Completed this project successfully within the scheduled time frame.

Professional Skills:

- AIA Engineering Recording and Production
- 1 year diploma Method Acting and Psychology
- CSCS Joinery & Carpentry
- Currently undertaking a Alison Diploma in Mental Health Studies in the Workplace

Projects, Hobbies & Interests:

Community Support

I assist support staff to help children with learning difficulties twice a month, supporting teaching staff with preparing meals, planning activities and provide general assistance. Occasionally my guitar comes out to 'entertain' the kids and give the staff a break/laugh!

Music Studio building

Scotch lake Studios Westside Studios

Project managed and built 2 sound proofed recording studios. Designed, budgeted and built from ground up, managing a small team of 3. Completed within 4 months and 2 moths respectively. Was delivered within budget and on time.

I occasionally produce and work with local musicians.

• St. Bernadette's School – Football coaching & refereeing Coached the 7-10 years olds in basic football techniques, drills and worked alongside the school manager in supporting and running the school teams. Have refereed on a number of occasions.

Carpentry & Joinery

Am a competent carpenter & joiner and am involved in a number of upcycling projects to restore old furniture, giving them a new lease of life and new home

Word Press site building

Have built and number of site for friends, family and professionally.

• I have a full UK driving licence

References available on request